Guide to the Teunis G. Bergen and Bergen family collection ARC.006
Brooklyn Historical Society
- Group 1: Teunis G. Bergen papers, 1411
  - Series 6: Personal papers, 1747-1881; 1415; 0.2 Linear Feet in one manuscript box
    Personal Papers includes Bergen's childhood school books, legal documents, travel logs, and other ephemera. The correspondence files in this series document many aspects of Bergen's life, including his appointments to the New Utrecht Board of Supervisors, as Commissioner of Records, and to the United States Congress; invitations to various civic functions; requests for land surveying; and correspondence with local residents about farming. The deeds, leases, and mortgages in this series document Bergen's land transactions in New Utrecht. Additionally, the series contains papers pertaining to Bergen's military service, as well as documents concerning the New York State Constitutional Conventions of 1846, 1854, and 1860.
    - Account books, 1864-1865; 1870-1871, 776 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - American Institute, 1837, 1840-1843; 1528 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Appointments, 1834-1880; 777 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Bay Ridge property - Abstract of title, nd; 778 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Belson, Frederick, 1872; 898 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Bergen, Teunis G. - Map of land owned in Monmouth County, New jersey, circa 1850-1881; 1533 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Bergen, Teunis G. - Photographic portrait, circa 1860-1880; 1530 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Bergen vs. Gulner, circa 1876; 893 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Bogart, Peter - Estate papers, 1871, 1877-1878; 1529 (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - Bonds, 1836-1876; 780 (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - Elizabeth Brainerd and Catherine Barr - Last Wills and Testaments, circa 19th century; 899 (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - Brooklyn Bureau of Charities: Annual report, circa 19th century; 947 (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - Brooklyn & Flatbush Turnpike: Court decision on ownership, 1867; 946 (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - Carriage house plans, circa 19th century; 888 (Box 18, Folder 24)
    - Catalog of books in Teunis Bergen's library, circa 1850-1881; 781 (Box 18, Folder 25)
    - Catherine and Main Street Ferry - Broadside, 1884; 948 (Box 18, Folder 26)
    - Cholera Epidemic - Article from the Board of Health, 1832; 949 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Commissioner of Records, 1856-1875; 782 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Common Council: Street Committee report, 1848; 950 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Congressional Representative: Certificates, 1864, 1867; 783 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1826-1859; 784 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence (official), 1828-1859; 890 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1832-1880; 951 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence (incoming), 1845-1877; 889 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1860-1881; 785 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence (outgoing), 1861-1868; 891 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Court papers, 1839, 1849; 786 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Cultivator subscription list, 1839-1861; 787 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Deeds, nd; 892 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Deeds and conveyances, 1747-1879; 801 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Drafts of legal agreements, 1841-1865; 789 (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Dutch records translation (misc.), circa 19th century; 895 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Dutch records translation (New Utrecht), circa 19th century; 894 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Dutch translations published in the Brooklyn Daily Eagle, 1874; 897 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Early Settlers of King's County: Subscription list, ca. 1880; 790 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Garretson, G.R.: Price List for Seeds, 1863-1865; 952 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Gashire, Judith: Narrative (translation from Dutch, 1766), circa 19th century; 896 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Historical narrative - Brooklyn tide mills, circa 1830-1881; 1531 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Historical narrative - The Old De Hart or Bergen house, circa 1830-1881; 1532 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Leases, 1832-1869; 791 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - List of persons to whom lots assessed, 1849; 1539 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Memorial for Teunis Bergen by Henry C. Murphy, 1881; 792 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Military papers, 1829, 1836-1837; 793 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous, 1834-1880; 953 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous, 1835, 1837-1838; 794 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Mortgages, 1835, 1837-1838; 795 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Newspapers, 1856-1879; 954 (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - New Jersey Farm (Keyport), 1857-1860; 796 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - New York State Convention, 1846, 1854, 1860; 802 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Obituary (from Brooklyn Daily Eagle), April 25, 1881; 803 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Plans for the building of a sailboat, 1845; 1534 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Provincial Convention - Elected delegates from Kings County, 1775; 955 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Receipts, 1843-1858; 804 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Report of the Committee Concerning the grading of 3rd Avenue between Bay Ridge and Fort Hamilton, 1861; 1536 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Road List, District No. 4, 1855; 1537 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - St. Nicholas Society, 1862, 1878; 805 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - School books, 1815-1816; 807 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - School books, 1818; 808 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - School books, 1819; 809 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - School books, 1820-1823; 810 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Seating plan of the U.S. House of Representatives and Senate, circa 1860s; 1538 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Stocks, 1869, 1872; 811 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Survey book, 1869; 887 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Surveys, 1850-1870 ca.; 812 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Table of distances from Brooklyn City Hall, circa 1830-1881; 1540 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Table of feet and inches in chains and links, circa 1830-1881; 1541 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Travel journals, 1856-1857; 1862; 813 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Van Pelt family - Estate papers, 1856-1861; 1876; 814 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Whitman, Walt - Correspondence to Teunis G. Bergen, 1849, 1851; 1655; 2 Linear Feet in 5 boxes. (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Series 7: Surveying records, 1704-1877; 1416; 4.6 Linear Feet in 11 boxes.
    Surveying records is organized into seven subseries and documents the various duties carried out by Teunis G. Bergen as a surveyor. The series is comprised primarily of maps and surveys of land owned by residents of Brooklyn and its environs, as well as roads and streets in the area, providing a glimpse into the evolution of Brooklyn's geography and physical infrastructure in the mid-to-late 19th century. Also included are drafts of legal documents, including deeds and legal land descriptions; building specifications of houses in Brooklyn; notes and calculations recorded by Bergen in the course of his surveying work; and title searches undertaken by Bergen to support his surveying work. The series is organized into seven subseries: Bound surveys; Drafts of legal documents; Field notes and calculations; Maps and surveys; Map tracings and land descriptions; Specifications of houses; and Title searches. Subseries 1 is comprised of five bound and numbered volumes, arranged in numerical order. Subseries 2, 3, 5, 6, and 7 are arranged alphabetically according to the personal name of a propert owner or the property's name. Subseries 4 is organized alphabetically by neighborhood name, and thereafter by the property owner's name.
    - Subseries 1: Bound surveys, circa 1850s; 1261
      - Books 1-3, circa 1850s; 1262 (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - Books 4 & 5, circa 1850s; 1263 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Subseries 2: Drafts of legal documents, 1845-1881; 1264
      - Barre, Ann, circa 19th century; 1265 (Box 23, Folder 3)
      - Belson, 1872; 1266 (Box 23, Folder 4)
      - Bennet, Charles C., 1878-1880; 1267 (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - Bennet, Clarence E., 1878; 1268 (Box 23, Folder 6)
      - Bennet, Cornelius, 1853; 1269 (Box 23, Folder 7)
      - Bennet, Gertrude, 1834, 1841; 1270 (Box 23, Folder 8)
      - Bennet, J.R., 1868; 1271 (Box 23, Folder 9)
      - Bennet, John C., 1856; 1272 (Box 23, Folder 10)
      - Bennet, John J., circa 1840-1880; 1273 (Box 23, Folder 11)
      - Bennet, R.R., 1853-1865; 1274 (Box 23, Folder 12)
      - Bennet, W.E., 1872; 1275 (Box 23, Folder 13)
      - Bennet, W.W., 1864, 1881; 1276 (Box 23, Folder 14)
      - Bennet, William, 1860, 1868, 1881; 1277 (Box 23, Folder 15)
      - Bennet, Winant, 1853-1854, 1857; 1278 (Box 23, Folder 16)
      - Bergen, Cornelius, circa 19th century; 1279 (Box 23, Folder 17)
      - Bergen, Elizabeth, 1857; 1280 (Box 23, Folder 18)
      - Bergen, Garret, 1859; 1281 (Box 23, Folder 19)
      - Bergen, Joanna, 1853; 1282 (Box 23, Folder 20)
      - Bergen, John, 1853-1854; 1283 (Box 23, Folder 21)
      - Bergen, Lefferts, 1853; 1284 (Box 23, Folder 22)
      - Bergen, Teunis, 1856, 1859; 1285 (Box 23, Folder 23)
      - Board of Supervisors, 1859; 1286 (Box 23, Folder 24)
      - Bogert, Peter, 1856, 1877, 1880; 1287 (Box 23, Folder 25)
      - Boyle, W.H., 1858; 1288 (Box 23, Folder 26)
      - Carson, Deorah, 1854, 1858-1859, 1863; 1289 (Box 23, Folder 27)
      - Cowenhoven, Annette, 1855-1856; 1290 (Box 23, Folder 28)
      - Cowenhoven, Cornelius, 1881; 1291 (Box 23, Folder 29)
      - Cowenhoven, Garret, 1856; 1292 (Box 23, Folder 30)
      - Cowenhoven, Nicholas, 1866, 1873; 1293 (Box 23, Folder 31)
      - Cowenhoven, Peter, 1854; 1294 (Box 23, Folder 32)
      - Cowenhoven, Phebe, nd, 1859; 1295 (Box 23, Folder 33)
      - Cropsey, Andrew, 1873; 1296 (Box 23, Folder 34)
      - Delaplaine, John, 1840; 1297 (Box 23, Folder 35)
      - Denyse, Tunis, 1853; 1298 (Box 23, Folder 36)
      - Duryea, Abraham & Maria, 1855; 1299 (Box 23, Folder 37)
      - Emmans, J.A., 1853, 1870, 1873, 1877; 1300 (Box 23, Folder 38)
      - Furman, Z., 1853; 1301 (Box 23, Folder 39)
      - Gelston, G.S., 1853; 1302 (Box 23, Folder 40)
      - Gravesend & Flatbush (Boundary Line), circa 19th century; 1303 (Box 23, Folder 41)
      - Hart, John, circa 19th century; 1304 (Box 23, Folder 42)
      - Hayman, John, 1858; 1305 (Box 24, Folder 1)
      - Hendrickson, J.B., 1856; 1306 (Box 24, Folder 2)
      - Hubbard, Samuel, 1853; 1307 (Box 24, Folder 3)
      - Hunt, Thomas, 1855; 1308 (Box 24, Folder 4)
      - Johnson, Jerome, 1856; 1309 (Box 24, Folder 5)
      - Kent, H.A., 1864, 1873; 1310 (Box 24, Folder 6)
      - Kouwenhoven, George, 1878; 1311 (Box 24, Folder 7)
      - Kouwenhoven, William J., 1856; 1312 (Box 24, Folder 8)
      - Langley, William, 1879; 1313 (Box 24, Folder 9)
      - Lefferts, John, 1856; 1314 (Box 24, Folder 10)
      - Lefferts, Robert B., 1855; 1315 (Box 24, Folder 11)
      - Lott, Charles, 1856, 1875; 1316 (Box 24, Folder 12)
      - Lott, Englebert & Jeremiah, 1863; 1317 (Box 24, Folder 13)
      - Lott, Jeremiah, circa 19th century; 1318 (Box 24, Folder 14)
      - Magaw, Lawrence, 1879; 1319 (Box 24, Folder 15)
      - Monfort, Andrew, 1879; 1320 (Box 24, Folder 16)
      - Pope, P. Bennet, 1863-1864; 1321 (Box 24, Folder 17)
      - Prince, Charles, 1853, 1856; 1322 (Box 24, Folder 18)
      - Rea, W.F., 1853, 1863; 1323 (Box 24, Folder 18)
      - Reformed Protestant Dutch Church (New Utrecht), 1872; 1324 (Box 24, Folder 19)
      - Schenck, Jeremiah, 1857; 1325 (Box 24, Folder 20)
      - Sedgwick, Theodore, 1880; 1326 (Box 24, Folder 21)
      - Stanton, Alexander, 1858; 1327 (Box 24, Folder 22)
      - Stanton, Henry, 1853, 1858; 1328 (Box 24, Folder 23)
      - Stillwell, Coert, 1868; 1329 (Box 24, Folder 24)
      - Stillwell, George, 1864, 1877; 1330 (Box 24, Folder 25)
      - Stillwell, Henry, circa 19th century; 1331 (Box 24, Folder 26)
      - Stillwell, Jaques, circa 19th century; 1332 (Box 24, Folder 27)
      - Stillwell, John, 1855; 1333 (Box 24, Folder 28)
      - Stillwell, Nicholas, 1861; 1334 (Box 24, Folder 29)
      - Stillwell, Phebe, 1859; 1335 (Box 24, Folder 30)
      - Stillwell, Richard, 1860; 1336 (Box 24, Folder 31)
      - Stryker Family, 1854, 1857; 1337 (Box 24, Folder 32)
      - Stryker, S.S., 1864; 1338 (Box 24, Folder 33)
      - Suydam, Tunis, circa 19th century; 1339 (Box 24, Folder 34)
      - Unidentifiable Names, circa 19th century; 1340 (Box 24, Folder 35)
      - Van Blankenstein, 1873; 1341 (Box 24, Folder 36)
      - Van Brunt, Albert, 1853, 1875; 1342 (Box 24, Folder 37)
      - Van Brunt, Daniel, 1865, 1874-1879; 1343 (Box 24, Folder 38)
      - Van Brunt, George, 1877, 1880; 1344 (Box 24, Folder 39)
      - Van Brunt, Jacques, circa 19th century; 1345 (Box 24, Folder 40)
      - Van Brunt, Rulif, nd; 1346 (Box 24, Folder 41)
      - Van Pelt, 1858, 1876; 1347 (Box 24, Folder 42)
      - Van Sicklen, circa 19th century; 1348 (Box 24, Folder 43)
      - Vanderbilt, John J., 1854; 1349 (Box 24, Folder 44)
      - Voorhees, Jacques & Jacobus, 1873; 1542 (Box 24, Folder 45)
      - Voorhees, John J., 1854; 1350 (Box 24, Folder 46)
      - Wardell, Simon G., 1859; 1351 (Box 24, Folder 47)
      - Wyckoff, B., 1845; 1352 (Box 24, Folder 48)
      - Wyckoff, H.R., 1868; 1353 (Box 24, Folder 49)
      - Wycoff, John & George, 1860; 1354 (Box 24, Folder 50)
      - Wyckoff, Peter, 1872; 1355 (Box 24, Folder 51)
      - Wyckoff, Van Brunt, 1856; 1356 (Box 24, Folder 52)
    - Subseries 3: Field notes and calculations, 1842-1870; 1166
      - Bath Property (New Utrecht), circa 1830-1881; 1167 (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - Bennet, C. (Gowanus), 1842; 1168 (Box 25, Folder 2)
      - Bennet, Christopher (New Utrecht), circa 1830-1881; 1169 (Box 25, Folder 3)
      - Bennet, Joseph, James & John, circa 1830-1881; 1170 (Box 25, Folder 4)
      - Bennet, Michael & John (New Utrecht), circa 1830-1881; 1171 (Box 25, Folder 5)
      - Bennet, R.R. (Fort Hamilton), 1863; 1172 (Box 25, Folder 6)
      - Bennet, William, circa 1830-1881; 1173 (Box 25, Folder 7)
      - Bennet, Winant, circa 1830-1881; 1174 (Box 25, Folder 8)
      - Bergen, Jane (Brooklyn), circa 1830-1881; 1175 (Box 25, Folder 9)
      - Bergen, John C. (Brooklyn), circa 1830-1881; 1176 (Box 25, Folder 10)
      - Bergen, Leffert, 1853; 1177 (Box 25, Folder 11)
      - Bergen, Teunis G. (New Utrecht), circa 1830-1881; 1178 (Box 25, Folder 12)
      - Bergen, Theodorus, 1853; 1179 (Box 25, Folder 13)
      - Bergen, Theodorus & Johnson, Coert (New Utrecht), 1845; 1180 (Box 25, Folder 14)
      - Botanical Garden (8th Ward, Brooklyn), circa 1830-1881; 1181 (Box 25, Folder 15)
      - Clarkson, M., 1865; 1182 (Box 25, Folder 16)
      - Clute (Fort Hamilton), 1857; 1183 (Box 25, Folder 17)
      - Copeland, Edward, 1861; 1184 (Box 25, Folder 18)
      - Cornell, L., circa 1830-1881; 1185 (Box 25, Folder 19)
      - Cortelyou (at the Narrows), circa 1830-1881; 1186 (Box 25, Folder 20)
      - Cow Lane (Flatbush), 1855; 1187 (Box 25, Folder 21)
      - Cowenhoven, Garret, 1855; 1188 (Box 25, Folder 22)
      - Cowenhoven, Johannes, circa 1830-1881; 1189 (Box 25, Folder 23)
      - Cowenhoven, Phebe (New Utrecht), 1852; 1190 (Box 25, Folder 24)
      - Cowenhoven & Backhouse, circa 1830-1881; 1191 (Box 25, Folder 25)
      - Crooke, P.S., 1851, 1853; 1192 (Box 25, Folder 26)
      - Cropsey, Jaques W., circa 1830-1881; 1193 (Box 25, Folder 27)
      - Cropsey, Valentine, 1842, 1854; 1194 (Box 25, Folder 28)
      - Cummings, Robert (Fort Hamilton), 1858; 1195 (Box 25, Folder 29)
      - De Russey, 1855; 1196 (Box 25, Folder 30)
      - Degroff, Abraham (New Utrecht), 1852; 1197 (Box 25, Folder 31)
      - Delaplaine (New Utrecht), 1852; 1198 (Box 25, Folder 32)
      - Denyse (New Utrecht), circa 1830-1881; 1199 (Box 25, Folder 33)
      - Dyker Meadows, 1863; 1200 (Box 25, Folder 34)
      - Emmans, Andrew, circa 1830-1881; 1201 (Box 25, Folder 35)
      - Emmans, J.A. & Lindley, John, 1860; 1202 (Box 25, Folder 36)
      - Flatbush Avenue, 1854, 1858; 1203 (Box 25, Folder 37)
      - Flatbush & New Lots (Boundary Line), 1852; 1204 (Box 25, Folder 38)
      - Flatbush & New Utrecht Plank Road, 1852; 1205 (Box 25, Folder 39)
      - Fourth Avenue, 1869; 1206 (Box 25, Folder 40)
      - Garretson, Elsie & Bergen, Michael, nd; 1207 (Box 25, Folder 41)
      - Geltson, George S. (Fort Hamilton), 1852-1853; 1208 (Box 25, Folder 42)
      - Gravesend Plank Road, 1853; 1209 (Box 25, Folder 43)
      - Griswold, Zachariah (Bay Ridge), 1855, 1857; 1210 (Box 25, Folder 44)
      - Grove, George & Benson, Egbert (New Utrecht), circa 1830-1881; 1211 (Box 25, Folder 45)
      - Hamilton Avenue, 1855; 1212 (Box 25, Folder 46)
      - Higgins, circa 1830-1881; 1213 (Box 25, Folder 47)
      - Hubbard, Samuel & Stryker, G. (Gravesend), 1853; 1214 (Box 25, Folder 48)
      - Hunt & Dalaphine, nd; 1215 (Box 25, Folder 49)
      - Kent, H.A., circa 1830-1881; 1216 (Box 25, Folder 50)
      - Kings County Alms House, 1858, 1862; 1217 (Box 26, Folder 1)
      - Lefferts, John (Flatbush), 1853, 1855; 1218 (Box 26, Folder 2)
      - Lefferts, Leffert Property (New Utrecht), 1850-1852; 1219 (Box 26, Folder 3)
      - Lefferts, Robert (New Utrecht), 1867; 1220 (Box 26, Folder 4)
      - Lott, John A. (New Utrecht), circa 1830-1881; 1221 (Box 26, Folder 5)
      - Lunatic Asylum (Flatbush), circa 1830-1881; 1222 (Box 26, Folder 6)
      - Martense, Garret (Flatbush), 1852; 1223 (Box 26, Folder 7)
      - Martense, George, 1859; 1224 (Box 26, Folder 8)
      - McGrath, circa 1830-1881; 1225 (Box 26, Folder 9)
      - Middle Street to 19th Street, 1850; 1226 (Box 26, Folder 10)
      - Murphy, Aaron, circa 1830-1881; 1227 (Box 26, Folder 11)
      - Murphy, Thomas (Gravesend), circa 1830-1881; 1228 (Box 26, Folder 12)
      - New Utrecht, circa 1830-1881; 1229 (Box 26, Folder 13)
      - New Utrecht, 1851, 1854; 1230 (Box 26, Folder 14)
      - New Utrecht (2nd & 4th Avenues), 1869; 1231 (Box 26, Folder 15)
      - Ovington Avenue, 1852; 1232 (Box 26, Folder 16)
      - Ovington, William A. (Yellow Hook), circa 1830-1881; 1233 (Box 26, Folder 17)
      - Penetentiary to Alms House (Grade Lines of Road), 1857; 1236 (Box 26, Folder 18)
      - Post Farm, circa 1830-1881; 1237 (Box 26, Folder 19)
      - Prince, C., circa 1830-1881; 1238 (Box 26, Folder 20)
      - Richards, Daniel (Yellow Hook), 1852-1854; 1239 (Box 26, Folder 21)
      - Road from Gravesend to Brooklyn, 1846-1849; 1240 (Box 26, Folder 22)
      - Rodgers Avenue (near Penitentiary), circa 1830-1881; 1241 (Box 26, Folder 23)
      - Ryder, Lawrence (Flatlands), 1858; 1242 (Box 26, Folder 24)
      - Second Avenue, 1870; 1243 (Box 26, Folder 25)
      - Stillwell, John (New Utrecht), 1855; 1244 (Box 26, Folder 26)
      - Stillwell, N., circa 1830-1881; 1245 (Box 26, Folder 27)
      - Stillwell Family (Gravesend), circa 1830-1881; 1246 (Box 26, Folder 28)
      - Stryker Family (Gravesend), 1857; 1247 (Box 26, Folder 29)
      - Suydam, Evert (New Utrecht), 1858; 1248 (Box 26, Folder 30)
      - Talmage, Thomas G. (Brooklyn), circa 1830-1881; 1249 (Box 26, Folder 31)
      - Third Avenue (Bay Ridge to Fort Hamilton), 1860; 1250 (Box 26, Folder 32)
      - Trumbull Estate, circa 1830-1881; 1251 (Box 26, Folder 33)
      - Twenty-Second Avenue, circa 1830-1881; 1252 (Box 26, Folder 34)
      - United States (Government Land at Fort Hamilton), circa 1830-1881; 1253 (Box 26, Folder 35)
      - Vanderbilt, Jeremiah (Flatbush), 1854; 1254 (Box 26, Folder 36)
      - Van Brunt, N.R. (near Bath), 1846; 1255 (Box 26, Folder 37)
      - Van Pelt, Henry, 1846; 1256 (Box 26, Folder 38)
      - Van Pelt, John (Brooklyn), 1852; 1257 (Box 26, Folder 39)
      - White, Matilda, 1860; 1258 (Box 26, Folder 40)
      - Wyckoff, P. (New Utrecht), circa 1830-1881; 1259 (Box 26, Folder 41)
      - Yellow Hook, 1851; 1260 (Box 26, Folder 42)
    - Subseries 4: Maps and surveys, 1704-1879; 1132
      - Bay Ridge, nd; 1067
        - Mackay, John, circa 1830-1881; 1068 (Box 27, Folder 1)
        - McGee, Owen, circa 1830-1881; 1069 (Box 27, Folder 2)
        - Van Brunt, Albert, 1875; 1078 (Box 27, Folder 3)
      - Brooklyn and Bushwick, 1704-1879; 979
        - Anderson & Clark, circa 1830-1881; 980 (Box 27, Folder 4)
        - Barr Estate (Near Prospect Park), 1876; 1073 (Box 27, Folder 5)
        - Bedford Avenue, 1844; 981 (Box 27, Folder 6)
        - Bennet, William (copy), 1696; 982 (Box 27, Folder 7)
        - Bennet, Winant (copy), 1696; 983 (Box 27, Folder 8)
        - Bergen Burial Ground, circa 1830-1881; 984 (Box 27, Folder 9)
        - Bergen, Derick, 1781; 985 (Box 27, Folder 10)
        - Bergen, Garret, 1839; 986 (Box 27, Folder 11)
        - Bergen, George, 1737; 988 (Box 27, Folder 12)
        - Bergen, Garret P., 1844; 987 (Box 27, Folder 13)
        - Bergen, Hans, 1728, 1763; 989 (Box 27, Folder 14)
        - Bergen, Jacob, 1750; 990 (Box 27, Folder 15)
        - Bergen, Jane, 1853; 991 (Box 27, Folder 16)
        - Bergen, John C., 1855; 992 (Box 27, Folder 17)
        - Bergen, John S., circa 1830-1881; 993 (Box 27, Folder 18)
        - Bergen, Lefferts, 1854; 994 (Box 27, Folder 19)
        - Bergen, Michael, circa 1830-1881; 995 (Box 27, Folder 20)
        - Bergen, Michael J., 1863; 996 (Box 27, Folder 21)
        - Bergen, Michael Hansen, 1723; 997 (Box 27, Folder 22)
        - Bergen, Theodorus, 1850, 1853; 998 (Box 27, Folder 23)
        - Berry, Rachel, circa 1830-1881; 999 (Box 27, Folder 24)
        - Bompjes Hook, circa 1830-1881; 1000 (Box 27, Folder 25)
        - Bowren, Watson, circa 1830-1881; 1001 (Box 27, Folder 26)
        - Brooklyn Penitentiary, circa 1830-1881; 1543 (Box 27, Folder 27)
        - Brooklyn Woodlands (copy), 1874; 1002 (Box 27, Folder 28)
        - Carson, Deborah, circa 1850-1865; 1003 (Box 27, Folder 29)
        - Clark & Anderson, 1851; 1544 (Box 27, Folder 30)
        - Cortelyou, Isaac, 1842; 1004 (Box 27, Folder 31)
        - Crooke, Margaret & P.S., circa 1830-1881; 1005 (Box 27, Folder 32)
        - DeBevoise, James, 1849; 1006 (Box 27, Folder 33)
        - Delaplaine, John, circa 1830-1881; 1007 (Box 27, Folder 34)
        - Delaplaine & Morris, circa 1830-1881; 1545 (Box 27, Folder 35)
        - Ditmas, Henry S., 1846; 1008 (Box 27, Folder 36)
        - Eighth Ward Farmland, circa 1830-1881; 1009 (Box 27, Folder 37)
        - Forble, Saul & Delaplain, circa 1830-1881; 1010 (Box 27, Folder 38)
        - Gowanus Cove, 1854-1855; 1011 (Box 27, Folder 39)
        - Greenwood Cemetery, 1844, 1853-1854; 1012 (Box 27, Folder 40)
        - Hunt, Thomas, 1844-1846, 1851; 1013 (Box 27, Folder 41)
        - Hussey, George, 1860; 1014 (Box 27, Folder 42)
        - Kent, Henry, 1846, 1873; 1015 (Box 28, Folder 1)
        - Lake, Johnson, 1846, 1849, 1851; 1016 (Box 28, Folder 2)
        - Lefferts, John, 1855; 1017 (Box 28, Folder 3)
        - Lott, Christopher, circa 1830-1881; 1074 (Box 28, Folder 4)
        - Lott, Jacobus, 1843-1844; 1018 (Box 28, Folder 5)
        - Lott, James, 1849; 1019 (Box 28, Folder 6)
        - Lott, Johannes, circa 1830-1881; 1020 (Box 28, Folder 7)
        - Martense, George, 1868; 1075 (Box 28, Folder 8)
        - Matbone, R., circa 1830-1881; 1021 (Box 28, Folder 9)
        - Morris, Leah, 1854; 1022 (Box 28, Folder 10)
        - Morris, Leah, 1867; 1076 (Box 28, Folder 11)
        - Ninth Ward, 1846; 1023 (Box 28, Folder 12)
        - Pope, Henry, 1848, 1864; 1024 (Box 28, Folder 13)
        - Powers Farm, 1723; 1025 (Box 28, Folder 14)
        - Property between 50th & 51st Streets and 7th Avenue, circa 1830-1881; 1546 (Box 28, Folder 15)
        - Rapalje, Johannes, 1769; 1026 (Box 28, Folder 16)
        - Ridgewood Park, 1868; 1077 (Box 28, Folder 17)
        - Rockwell, William, 1839, 1841; 1027 (Box 28, Folder 18)
        - Ryerson Family, 1851; 1028 (Box 28, Folder 19)
        - Saul, Jonathan, 1844; 1029 (Box 28, Folder 20)
        - Schermerhorn, Abraham, 1761; 1030 (Box 28, Folder 21)
        - Sixth Ward, Circa 1800s; 1486 (Box 28, Folder 22)
        - Smith, Samuel, 1851; 1031 (Box 28, Folder 23)